Guide to the Office of Housing and Residence Life records, 1937-2003 RG0051
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Office of Housing and Residence Life records
1937-2003
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
George Washington University. Office of Housing and Residence Life
RG0051
14.75 Linear Feet
Collection includes manuals, annual reports, rosters, photographs, books, and artifacts.
Restrictions on Access
Series 1, 2, and 4 are closed to research for 50 years from date of record creation.
Acquisition Information
Materials acquired through transfers from Office of Housing and Residence Life.
Historical Note
The Office of Housing and Residence Life of The George Washington University is under the Senior Vice President for Student and Academic Support Services. In 1997 it became part of the Community Living and Learning Center (CLCC), and the Office of the Dean of Students oversees its operation. It manages on-campus housing for students and establishes rules and procedures for governing them. Students and staff work together to ensure that life in the residence halls contributes to the growth of both individual students and the larger residence hall community through academic discourse, community discussion, responsible decision-making, and a variety of recreational and cultural events.
Collection Scope and Content
Materials in this collection include manuals, annual reports, rosters, photographs, books, and artifacts. They range in date from 1937-2003, and were transferred to the University Archives by the Director of Housing and Residence Life. Please note: Not all series are processed. Ask staff for assistance.
Collection Organization
Organized into four series: Departmental files; Rosters; Watergate exhibit; and Housing and food services.
Recreation; Dormitories; Staff; Food service; Washington (D.C.); Universities and colleges -- Food service -- Washington (D.C.); Photographs; Foggy Bottom (Washington, D.C.); George Washington University
- Departmental files, 1962-1989; RG0051 Series 1; 9 Linear feet
  Scope and Contents note
  This series contains manuals, annual reports, and Residence Hall Association materials. Topics include president's report, food service, and material related to the work of the residence hall staff. The material dates from 1962-1989. The Residence Hall Staff Manuals Include orientation, programming, drug policy, security, summer intersession policy, fire safety and bomb procedures, processes for non-payment on lease, Christmas closing policy, job descriptions, judicial system, emergency info, resident hall regulations and policies, summer storage policy, charges for damages, roster, etc.
  - Residence Hall Staff Manual, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Residence Hall Staff Manual, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Residence Hall Staff Manual, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Residence Hall Staff Manual, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Residence Hall Staff Manual, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Residence Hall Staff Manual, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Residence Hall Staff Manual [1/2], 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Residence Hall Staff Manual [2/2], 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    General note
    Attached AA manual, "Hopefully, Everything about Being an AA"
  - Residence Hall Staff Manual, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Residence Hall Staff Manual, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Residence Hall Staff Manual, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Residence Hall Staff Manual, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Residence Hall Staff Manual, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Residence Hall Staff Manual, 1982-1983 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Residence Hall Staff Manual, 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Residence Hall Staff Manual, 1984-1985 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Residence Hall Staff Manual, 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Residence Hall Staff Manual, 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Residence Hall Staff Manual, 1987-1988 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Residence Hall Staff Manual, 1988-1989 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Office of Housing and Residence Life: Operating budget report, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    Fiscal year
  - Office of Housing and Residence Life: Director of Housing annual report, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Office of Housing and Residence Life: Annual Reports, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    Fiscal year; Director of Housing and Assistant Director of Residence Life
  - Office of Housing and Residence Life: Annual Reports, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Fiscal year; Assistant Director of Residence Life annual and programming report; Assistant Dean of Students programming report; Thurston Hall and Housing Services Report
  - Office of Housing and Residence Life: Annual Reports, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Office of Housing and Residence Life: Annual Reports, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    Fiscal year; Assistant Director of Residence Life; ResCounselor; Program Coordinator
  - Office of Housing and Residence Life: Annual Reports, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    Fiscal year; Assistant Director of Residence Life; ResCounselor; Assistant Director of Housing Services
  - Office of Housing and Residence Life: Annual Reports, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Office of Housing and Residence Life: Annual Reports, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    Fiscal year; Assistant Director of Residence Life; ResCounselor; Assistant Director of Housing Services; Program Coordinator
  - Office of Housing and Residence Life: Annual Reports, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    Fiscal year; Assistant Director of Residence Life; Assistant Director of Housing Services; Program Coordinator
  - Office of Housing and Residence Life: Annual Reports, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Office of Housing and Residence Life: Annual Reports, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    Fiscal year; Assistant Director of Residence Life; Resident Counselor; Assistant Director of Housing Services; Program Coordinator
  - Office of Housing and Residence Life: Annual Reports, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    Fiscal year; summer of 1983 reported separately; Assistant Director of Residence Life; Resident Counselor; Assistant Director of Housing Services; Assistant Director of Special Projects
  - Office of Housing and Residence Life: Annual Reports, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    Fiscal year; summer of 1984 reported separately; Assistant Director of Residence Life; Resident Counselor; Assistant Director of Housing Services; Assistant Director of Special Projects
  - Office of Housing and Residence Life: Annual Reports, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    Fiscal year; summer of 1985 reported separately; Fiscal year; summer of 1983 reported separately; Assistant Director of Residence Life; Resident Counselor; Assistant Director of Housing Services; Assistant Director of Special Projects
  - Office of Housing and Residence Life: Annual Reports, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    Fiscal year; summer of 1986 filed separately; Director of Housing and Residence Life summary report; Assistant Director of Housing Services; Assistant Director of Special Projects; Assistant Director of Resident Life files for Fall 1986 and Spring 1987 filed separately
  - Office of Housing and Residence Life: Annual Reports, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    Fiscal year; Assistant Director of Resident Life files for Fall 1986 and Spring 1987 filed separately; Director of Housing and Residence Life summary report; Assistant Director of Housing Services; Assistant Director of Special Projects
  - Office of Housing and Residence Life: Annual Reports, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    Fiscal year; summer of 1988 filed separately; Assistant Director of Resident Life files for Fall 1987 and Spring 1988 filed separately; Assistant Director of Housing Services; Assistant Director of Special Projects
  - Office of Housing and Residence Life: Annual Reports, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    Fiscal year; Assistant Director of Residence Life, Fall 1988 report
  - Residence Hall Association: President's Report, 1977-1978 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    Steven Weisel
  - Residence Hall Association: President's Report, 1981-1982 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    Paula Dubberly
  - Residence Hall Association: President's Report, 1982-1983 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    Steve Gousie
  - Residence Hall Association: President's Report, 1983-1984 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    Dale Hamilton
  - Residence Hall Association: NCC Annual Report, 1984-1985 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    Anita Russell, NCC; RHA President Paul Tarlow did not submit report
  - Residence Hall Association: President's Report, 1985-1986 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    Mitchell G. Schuckman
  - Residence Hall Association: NCC Report, 11/1984 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    NAACURH Conference at Kent State University
  - Residence Hall Association: President's Report, 1986-1987 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    Craig S. Fisher
  - Residence Hall Association: President's Report, 1987-1988 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Residence Hall Association, 1976-1983 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    Miscellaneous materials
  - Residence Hall Association, 1983-1984 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    Miscellaneous material
  - Residence Hall Association, 1984-1985 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Residence Hall Association, 1985-1986 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Residence Hall Association, 1986-1987 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Residence Hall Association, 1987-1988 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - MMBB Miscellaneous Materials, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    Original finding aid does not explain abbreviation
  - MMBB Miscellaneous Materials, 1984-1986 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - MMBB Miscellaneous Materials, 1987-1988 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Joint Food Service Board, 1982-1984 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Joint Food Service Board, 1984-1985 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Joint Food Service Board, 1985-1986 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Joint Food Service Board, 1986-1987 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Joint Food Service Board, 1987-1988 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Food Service files, 1962-1968 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Food Service files, 1969-1975 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Food Service files, 1975-1979 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Food Service files, 1979-1984 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Food Service files, 1984-1985 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Food Service files, 1985-1986 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Food Service files, 1986-1987 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Food Service files, 1987-1988 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Kosher Food file, 1964-1988 (Box 6, Folder 32)
- Rosters, 1987-1990; RG0051 Series 2; 1.5 Linear feet (Box 2)
  This series contains residence hall rosters. This material covers the dates 1987-90.
  - System Roster, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - System Roster, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - System Roster, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Watergate exhibit, 1970-1974; RG0051 Series 3; 4 Linear feet (Box 0, Box 7, Box 1, Box 2, Box 3, Box 4, Box 5, Box 6)
  This series contains framed photos newspaper articles, books, transcripts, audio cassettes, and artifacts. The material dates from 1970-74. The subject of the exhibit was the Watergate scandal. This material was part of an exhibit originally mounted in the former museum room at the Hall on Virginia Avenue. This room served as the lookout by the Watergate burgles.
  - Washington Star News newspaper clipping. Headline states: "Ford Becomes President", 08/04/1974 (Box NOT SPECIFIED, Folder 1)
  - Washington Post newspaper front page with headline "Nixon Resigns", 8/9/1974 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Washington Post montage of satirical, political cartoons about Richard Nixon by Herblock, 8/9/1974 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Photograph of Nixon and his family, including his wife, two daughters, and sons-in law, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Photograph portrait of Richard Nixon smiling with facsimile autograph, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Photograph of White House lawn with helicopter in the distance, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Copy of Richard Nixon's resignation letter, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Picture of Gerald and Betty Ford on the cover of Newsweek, 8/19/1974 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Baltimore Sun newspaper clipping with headline "Agnew Resigns", 10/11/1973 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Photograph of Richard and Pat Nixon stepping out of Air Force One, undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Photograph of Pat Nixon with children and clown, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Photograph of President Richard Nixon playing with dog in Florida, undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Photograph of President Richard Nixon speaking, beside him is his wife and daughter Tricia, undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Photograph of President Richard Nixon on the day of his resignation, undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Photograph of Gerald and Betty Ford, David and Julie (Nixon) Eisenhower on day of Nixon's resignation, undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Collage of 16 images that include a wig used by the CIA, cash kept by the five burglars, and the smoke detector bug, undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Picture of Richard and Pat Nixon on their daughter Tricia's wedding day, undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Picture of Richard Nixon's last day as President. He is waving to the people before boarding the helicopter, undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Picture of Richard Nixon and Golda Meir, Israel's Prime Minister, undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - The Inaugural Story 1789-1969 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    American Heritage Magazine, eds. and The 1969 Inaugural Book Committee. The Inaugural Story 1789-1969. Washington, D.C.: American Heritage Publishing Co., Inc., 1969.
  - All The President's Men, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    Bernstein, Carl and Bob Woodward. All The President's Men. New York: Simon and Schuster, 1974.
  - A Good Life: Newspapering and Other Adventures, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    Bradlee, Ben. A Good Life: Newspapering and Other Adventures. New York: Simon and Schuster, 1995.
  - Chief Counsel: Inside the Ervin Committee-The Untold Story of Watergate, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    Dash, Samuel. Chief Counsel: Inside the Ervin Committee-The Untold Story of Watergate. New York: Random House, 1976.
  - Inside the Oval Office: The White House Tapes from FDR to Clinton, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    Doyle, William. Inside the Oval Office: The White House Tapes from FDR to Clinton. New York: Kodansha America, Inc., 1999.
  - We Interrupt This Broadcast, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    Garner, Joe. We Interrupt This Broadcast. Naperville, IL: Sourcebooks, Inc., 1998.
  - The White House Transcripts, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    Gold, Gerald, ed. The White House Transcripts. New York: The Viking Press, 1973.
  - The Haldeman Diaries: Inside the Nixon White House, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    Haldeman, H.R. The Haldeman Diaries: Inside the Nixon White House. New York: G.P. Putnam's Sons, 1994.
  - Abuse of Power: The New Nixon Tapes, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    Kutler, Stanley I. Abuse of Power: The New Nixon Tapes. New York: Simon and Schuster, 1997.
  - Will: The Autobiography of G. Gordon Liddy, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    Liddy, G. Gordon. Will: The Autobiography of G. Gordon Liddy. New York: St. Martin's Press, 1996. (Autographed with inscription "For Room 723, my old 'lookout' Best Wishes Room, G. Gordon Liddy")
  - Submission of Recorded Presidential Conversations to the Committee on The Judiciary of the House of Representatives, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    Nixon, Richard. Submission of Recorded Presidential Conversations to the Committee on The Judiciary of the House of Representatives. Washington, D.C .: U.S. Government Printing Office, 1974.
  - The Final Days, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    Woodward, Bob and Carl Bernstein. The Final Days. New York: Simon and Schuster, 1976.
  - Shadow: Five Presidents and the Legacy of Watergate, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    Woodward, Bob. Shadow: Five Presidents and the Legacy of Watergate. New York: Simon and Schuster, 1999.
  - U.S. News and World Report. "Rethinking Nixon", 1999 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    U.S. News and World Report. "Rethinking Nixon" New York: U.S. News and World Report Inc., September 20, 1999.
  - Two copies of a transcript on the telephone conversation between the President and Richard Kleindienst, 04/19/1971 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    From 3:04 to 3:09 p.m.
  - Transcript of a recording of a meeting between the President and H.R. Haldeman in the Oval Office, 06/23/1972 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Transcript of a recording of a meeting among the President, John Dean, and H.R. Haldeman in the Oval Office, 03/21/1973 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Plaque reading "Watergate Room", undated (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - The Late Great Planet Earth, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    Lindsey, Hal with C.C. Carlson. The Late Great Planet Earth. Michigan: Zondervan Publishing House, 1970.
  - Notes On The Old System: To Transform American Politics, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    Raskin, Marcus. Notes On The Old System: To Transform American Politics. New York: David McKay Company, Inc., 1974.
  - Without Honor: The Impeachment of President Nixon and the Crimes of Camelot, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    Zeifman, Jerry. Without Honor: The Impeachment of President Nixon and the Crimes of Camelot. New York: Thunder's Mouth Press, 1995.
  - Reference Cassette #E151 Abuse of Government Power Tapes, undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Reference Cassette #E154 Abuse of Government Power Tapes, undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Reference Cassette #E2 Watergate Trial Tapes "Smoking Gun" - U.S. v. John N. Mitchell, undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Reference Cassette #E7 1 and 2 Watergate Trial Tapes "Cancer on the Presidency" - U.S. v. John N. Mitchell. Et al, undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Reference Cassette #E30 Watergate Special Prosecution Force, undated (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Reference Cassette #E149 Abuse of Government Power Tapes, undated (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - White button with words "PRESIDENT" in blue and "NIXON" in red, undated (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - 18" caricature doll of Nixon, undated (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Nixon Halloween mask, undated (Box 7, Folder 12)
- Housing and food services, 1937-2003; RG0051 Series 4; 0.25 Linear feet (Box 1)
  This series contains brochures, flyers, memorandums, applications, map, surveys, apartments lease, floor plans, guides, correspondence, and job descriptions. They range in date from 1937 to 2003. The materials concern political science and the imagination; summer housing; resident assistants; room assignments; food service in residence halls; fire and emergency procedures; group housing; rules and regulations; "Stag"; specific residence halls; dedications; cornerstone ceremonies; cost of rooms; men's housing; women's housing; co-ed housing; storage; food services on campus, and off campus housing.
  - Food Services, 1965-2001 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Housing and Residence Life, 06/1970-1979 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Housing and Residence Life Brochures, 1970 ca. --1992 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Residence Halls, 1968-1992 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Residence Halls 1957 E Street, 04/15/2003 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Residence Halls--Adams Hall, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Residence Halls - Fulbright Hall (formerly Everglades Hall), 05/06/1996 --04/15/2003 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Residence Halls Guides to Residence Halls, 1964-1980, 1962-1980 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Residence Halls Guides to Residence Halls, 1981-2003, 1981 --04/15/2003 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Residence Halls Hall on Virginia Avenue (HOVA), 10/12/1999 --04/15/2003 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Residence Halls JKBO Hall, 05/16/1995 --04/15/2003 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Residence Halls--Mitchell Hall, 07/01/1971 --04/15/2006 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Residence Halls New Hall, 1996 --04/15/2003 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Residence Halls--Regulations & Information, 1968-1989 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Residence Halls--Staughton Hall (707 22nd St.), undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Residence Halls--Strong Hall, 05/07/1937 --04/15/2003 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Residence Halls--Thurston Hall, 1964 --04/15/2003 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - The Hue and Cry, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    Scope and Contents
    Two issues of the Hue and Cry, a monthly journal devoted to the dealings and doings of the Men's Residence Hall, October and December 1966.